[The Old Story of Yu Hong]
[Episode 29]
Hao Jie is already in Shanghai,
receiving treatment at a hospital.
The doctors there are really good.
Don't worry.
Her illness can definitely be cured.
Here,
eat this apple.
Weiguo,
when are we going to see a movie?
What did you say?
I want to see a movie.
What did you call me?
You're back.
I'll pay back that 300,000 yuan.
What do you mean by that?
You think I spent that 300,000 yuan
to buy you away from her?
Take a good look at yourself.
Do you really think
you're worth that much?
If you're leaving, then get the hell out.
I don't need your 300,000 yuan
for your freedom.
Thanks.
Thank you.
Keep going and we'll be out of the city.
I'm so confused.
Ms. Wan said to head south,
but she never said how far south.
Vietnam is south,
and so is South Africa.
We can't just keep going
until we reach the South Pole, can we?
Oh, give me a break.
Vietnam isn't south.
It's over to the west.
Quit talking nonsense.
Have you ever read a book?
Vietnam is down by Inner Mongolia.
Really?
Then I must've gotten it mixed up.
You're the man.
Oh, right.
A few days ago,
a few shop owners found out
Dong had gone missing,
and they stopped paying
their protection fees.
I went to Zhang's butcher shop.
The second I walked in,
they glared at me,
then grabbed a knife and chased me out.
Let me tell you.
I was thinking about going
to the bathhouse the other day,
but they asked me
for a bath ticket at the entrance.
When Dong was around,
who would've dared give us any lip?
How about
we call the police?
We can't call the police.
Dong has gone into the jaws
of danger to hone himself.
When he comes out, he'll make a name
for himself far and wide.
He's off doing something big.
Calling the police now
would interrupt his cultivation.
And that would make you...
A traitor!
You're the man.
When it matters most, you find out
who's loyal and who's not.
You can tell who's a true brother
by how he acts now.
hat are you doing?
[Yuhong Square Police Station]
Officer Ma.
What time is it?
[Yuhong Square Police Station]
Hurry home.
All right, all right.
[Golden Imperial Dance Hall]
The last time Dong called me
into his office,
he put his hand on my shoulder
and said to me earnestly,
"Man,
this time, you've got a big job to do."
Then...
what was it?
What's this?
Your sideburns?
Brain.
Dong said
we need to use our brains
when we're doing things.
Right.
Dong did say
we had a big job to do.
But the last time I asked him
what it was,
he... he wouldn't tell me either.
Do you remember?
There was this one time
Dong said he was going to meet someone,
and he wouldn't let us come along.
That's right.
San Yan'er's brother-in-law has a sister.
Dong even had me
look into her a while back.
He said she's a cop
and that we should get to know her,
build a good relationship with her.
I get it now.
Dong must've been sent by the police
to go undercover.
Usually, when I go out
to stock up on cigarettes,
he only sends me away for a day or two.
This time, he sent me to Guangzhou
for so long
so I could learn
from the KTVs there.
We can't let Dong down.
If Dong really did go undercover,
then we really ought
to start doing some legitimate business.
You're the one who gets it, Meng.
Dong said
we need to use our brains.
Karaoke halls in Guangzhou
aren't called dance halls.
[Responsible Entertainment,
Worry-Free Singing]
They're called KTVs.
[Say No to Vice, Keep Our Karaoke Clean]
You don't hug and cuddle
on the dance floor,
[Stay Clean, Sing Healthy,
Promote a Better Culture]
and you don't have to wait
to request a song.
[Welcome]
[Come Sing Out on a Night in Tiecheng]
[A Huge Selection of Hits, Sing What You Like]
[Drinks & Snacks, Perfect for Casual Gatherings]
They're all private rooms—
[20% Off All Drinks] [Set A: 58]
separate, discreet, and civilized.
That's what a proper KTV should be like.
Throw out all those fake cigarettes
and fake liquor.
Don't keep any of it.
From now on, we only sell cigarettes
and liquor from legitimate sources.
Even if the Industry and Commerce Bureau
comes to inspect us,
we've got nothing to worry about.
We're not in this for a quick buck.
We've got to think long-term, understand?
And the staff there
aren't like ours.
Just look at
what our staff are like.
From now on, our staff
have to be professional
and follow standardized procedures.
Things can't be like they used to be.
-Did you get a nose job, sis?
-No, I didn't.
You look different to me.
I haven't changed.
Don't be ridiculous.
Why are you still hanging around here?
From now on, we're done holding hands,
kissing guests, letting them
touch our thighs, and all that.
If we can't kiss them, what can we do?
-Exactly.
-Why can't we kiss anymore?
-Seriously.
Why?
Yun, didn't I tell you
there's a chant?
You're supposed to teach them.
-What chant?
What chant?
Come on, Yun. Show them how it's done.
Did all that teaching go to waste?
Get down here.
Show some decorum.
The leader is right here.
Come on, hurry up.
Loud and clear, okay? Raise your voice.
Okay.
One, two, three.
-Welcome!
What's wrong?
Why isn't he saying anything?
What's going on?
-Where is he going?
-Why is he leaving?
What's wrong with him?
What happened?
[May Buddha's Light Shine Upon You
and Bring Prosperity to Your Business]
[Golden Imperial Dance Hall]
[Grand Opening! Everyone Is Welcome]
Ms. Wan said
11:00 is the auspicious time
to open for business.
My watch has stopped.
Do you guys know what time it is?
What time is it?
Mine says 11:05.
Oh, give me a break.
Mine says 10:50.
Why does mine say 12:00?
Is yours keeping accurate time?
Mine runs a little slow.
Then won't that make you an idiot?
Meng, do you know what time it is?
Around noon.
So, are we doing this or not?
Hurry up.
[Golden Imperial Dance Hall]
You scared me.
Are you an idiot?
[Grand Opening! Everyone Is Welcome]
Let's do one.
If we're doing it,
shouldn't we all do it together?
You...
You're unbelievable.
All right,
we're done here, right?
Let's finish up and head back.
I'm freezing my ass off here.
Let's go. Let's go.
[Grand Opening! Everyone Is Welcome]
This is a tough crew to manage.
[Golden Imperial Dance Hall—Grand Opening]
That little belly of yours
is getting pretty round.
Why are these pants
so short?
Did they shrink?
No way.
Didn't we just buy them?
How did they get so much shorter?
These shoes are uncomfortable.
They're pinching my toes.
If they're pinching your toes,
don't wear these for now. Here,
step into these.
These are a little tight too, aren't they?
Let me see how tall you've gotten.
Come here.
Let me take a look.
Stand up straight.
You've grown so much!
Of course you've grown.
You've been here for so long.
Let's go.
I'll take you shoe shopping, okay?
We'll get you
some new clothes and pants, too.
Here, let me wrap this little scarf
around you.
This little vest is pretty nice too.
Let's get the shoes first.
Your feet are growing way too fast.
Here, take a look. See which one you like.
This one.
This one?
Good choice.
Do you have this in a size 27?
Yes, this is the one.
Then bring me both. Let's try them on.
Come on, try them on.
Sit here.
[Lisiman Bedding]
This one is pretty good.
No, this one won't do.
Turn around and look
at the one behind you.
That one's higher.
It's easier on your back when you're
holding the baby. You get it?
Yeah, that one's quite a bit higher
than this one.
Liu Yang,
give me a hand.
[Watch Your Step]
Let's go over there
and have a look
at those small mattresses.
The cornflakes—
kids actually like those.
Move it closer to her.
It's fine.
You don't have to worry about her.
I'm afraid the fried one
might prick her mouth.
Want some juice?
Have some juice.
Pineapple juice is fine.
She just loves sweet things.
All kids love sweet things.
-Have a bite.
-Isn't it good?
What's gotten into you today?
Getting all shy?
The cake's here.
This is too much. You shouldn't
have gone to all this trouble.
Just eat as much as you can, Juan.
The dessert came out a little early.
Cake—Qianqian likes cake, right?
She does.
She loves sweet things.
Come on,
that's enough. Quit pretending and eat.
Come on.
Give it a try.
What's wrong today?
Not much of an appetite.
I'll eat it.
M-Maybe she doesn't like the taste.
She's just a little shy.
She's like this whenever
there are a lot of people around.
I'll eat it.
Is it okay?
It's good, it's good, it's good.
It's a little cold.
I'm going to the bathroom.
-I-I'll go with you.
-Keep eating. Don't wait for me.
I'll go with you.
It's fine. You don't have to. Sit down.
Sit down. Sit down.
Be careful.
All right, quit pretending and drink up.
She's had it pretty rough, too.
Has Hao Jie
not been in touch lately?
No.
None of you men are any good.
Qianqian, eat up. Here.
You were little back then.
You don't remember.
Mom would cry her eyes out all night,
while Dad wouldn't say a word.
He'd just stay
on the balcony, chain-smoking.
Eventually, everyone in the neighborhood
started talking,
and that's when I found out
Dad was cheating on Mom.
I don't know that woman's name,
but I've always hated her.
Later,
later, when Sun Zheng
went to Guangzhou...
I finally
saw you men for what you are.
You men are
all a bunch of heartless bastards
who get tired of the old
and want something new.
Juan,
it really was my fault that Hao Jie and I
couldn't stay together.
I'm not even myself anymore.
I don't get to decide
what I've become.
What are you babbling about?
Why are you getting all weird, too?
What nonsense are you talking about?
Why haven't you eaten much?
We did eat. We did.
We were waiting for you.
Don't wait for me. The kid's hungry.
It's fine. Don't worry about her.
I don't know
what's gotten into her today.
She's just sitting here
like she's been glued to her seat.
You eat first. You eat first.
Okay, okay, okay.
Are you okay?
I'm fine. I just
drank too much water before we left.
It's fine, it's fine.
Eat. Eat.
If you don't like it, just give it to me.
Is it good?
Okay. It's good.
You left the house
without even fixing your collar.
What a goof.
Hey,
where are you?
Did you get some fries?
Where are you now?
Well, look
who finally crawled out of the grave.
After all this time,
you finally remembered
you have a daughter of your own.
What,
you finally topped up your phone?
Your daughter has been here
with me all this time,
and you've been completely out of touch.
You think you're some kind
of baby-delivering Bodhisattva?
When she asks me who her father is,
I'll tell her it was a mantis.
After he fathered her,
the female mantis ate him.
Juan,
it's me, He Liang.
How many times have you two talked?
I had no idea.
Qianqian's got a good memory.
She memorized my phone number
and likes to call me and chat in dialect
whenever she's got nothing to do.
That's her dialect,
not yours.
Aren't you basically just using her
as a language-learning tool?
We're learning from each other.
You...
Have you learned a few Cantonese phrases?
I don't speak Cantonese.
I only know those two lines from the song.
What song?
Sing it for me.
The one on your tape recorder.
♪ Cold and warm, when can they rest? ♪
♪ Looking back, how many autumns? ♪
All right,
I don't sing very well.
You sing great.
That's impressive.
Oh, stop it.
I don't even know what the lyrics mean.
It's good.
Has Qianqian gotten any taller?
I don't see much of a difference.
She still looks about the same size.
Have you gotten any taller?
How could I still be growing?
Look how old I am.
If I got any taller,
I'd turn into a giantess.
How's work been lately?
Same as always.
Don't force yourself
to make conversation.
Have you run out of things to say?
I just wanted to chat with you.